# **Essaid Serhani**

Orlando, FL | 407-808-6553 | dias 19@hotmail.com | Portfolio link: https://purelight4ever.github.io/

# **Web Developer**

### **Profile**

A Web developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including JavaScript, html5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, ES6, AJAX, JSON, RESTful API, Git, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, JSX, MongodB, PostgreSQL and MS-SQL Server. Quickly learn and master new technology; equally successful in both team and self-directed settings.

## Certifications

- Font end web developer (Free Code Camp)
- SQL Server DBA (Udemy)
- Real World SQL Server (Udemy)
- C# .NET Development (Basic & Intermediate)

- . Advanced Databases & SQL Querying (Udemy)
- . JavaScript (basic, intermediate) (Udemy)
- . Full Stack Web Developer Boot camp (Udemy)
- . The Complete Web Development (Udemy)

# Languages

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, ES6, RESTful API, Git, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, JSX, MongodB, PostgreSQL & MS-SQL Server

# **Professional Experience**

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | MAX PROCESSING. INC | ORLANDO, FL |

**11/2017 TO PRESENT** 

- · Full stack Developed and implemented web applications on multiple platforms.
- · Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- · Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web apps.
- Worked with Stingray Platform using HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, JavaScript, SQL server, NodeJS, AJAX, JSON, REST API & Pascal.
- · Strong problem solving and issue resolution skills with attention to details.
- · Self-start with strong self-management and problem-solving skills.
- · Demonstrated experience working in a collaborative team environment.
- · Ability to multi-task and manage several projects simultaneously.
- · Test applications on various browsers and modify if necessary.
- · Knowledge of image authoring & editing tools, to be able to crop, resize and enhanced...

#### WEB DEVELOPER | COGNIZANT. INC | TAMPA, FL |

01/2017 TO 10/2017

- · Built, tested and deployed scalable web application products.
- · Implemented innovative systems for data collection, storage and management of customer orders.
- · Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- Writing cross-browser compliant HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, NodeJS, ReactJS, ES6, Bootstrap, SQL server & MongodB.

#### FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER | MPNA. INC | ORLANDO, FL |

06/2012 TO 12/2016

- · Oversaw troubleshooting of technical issues to solve problems within a reasonable time frame.
- · Established milestones for projects and ensured that all team members were ready to meet deadlines
- · Designed and implemented web pages and sites for continues improvement in fast-paced environment.
- · Utilized programming capabilities in HTML, CSS, SQL, JQuery, JavaScript and other libraries as needed.
- · Implemented Google Campaigns and SEO for various types of websites.

#### DESKTOP TECHNICAL SUPPORT | AMERICAN RING | ORLANDO, FL |

04/2006 TO 06/2012

· Serviced major hardware and software problems.

#### **Education**

ASSOCIATE DEGREE | ISTA. UNIVERSITY FRONT END WEB DEVELOPMENT | FREE CODE CAMP